hydraforce.com 2019-06-22

# HydraForce - Hydraulic Cartridge Valves, Custom Manifolds and Electro-Hydraulic Control Systems Warranty and Terms

**The following information is detailed below:**

• What personally identifiable information of yours or third-party personal identification is collected from you through the website  
• The organization collecting the information  
• How the information is used  
• With whom the information may be shared  
• What choices are available to you for collection, use, and distribution of the information  
• The kind of security procedures in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under HydraForce’s control  
• How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information If you have questions or concerns about this Internet Privacy Statement   
  and/or the privacy practices of this website, you should first contact the HydraForce Marketing Department at   

Commitment to Confidentiality:

Confidentiality is a top priority at HydraForce. We are committed to maintaining the highest level of confidentiality with all of the information we receive from this website's users. This Internet Privacy Statement assures you that the information you share with HydraForce is kept confidential and fully secure.

Collection and Use of Personal Information:

Users of this website have the option to provide certain personal information. This personal information may be required in order to receive specific downloads or literature. By providing such information, you are agreeing that HydraForce may store, process, and review such information, and we may use this personal information for the purpose for which it was collected. 

We may collect certain personally identifiable information from our users at different places within this website. Our definition of personally identifiable information includes any information that may be used to specifically identify or contact you, such as your name, mail address, telephone number, cellular phone number, text message number, fax number, e-mail address, etc.

Customers, Distributors and Employees of HydraForce have the ability to register for access to the secured area of this website. To access the secured area, you may need to provide additional information such as name, address, email address and company. The purpose of the registration process is to verify and validate who is requesting access to the secured area of the website. Registration also enables us to tailor the information you receive.

We may use the voluntarily provided contact information to notify website users of updates to existing products and services, new products and services, or upcoming events. Website users who do not wish to receive such notifications via e-mail can choose to opt-out of receiving such information. It is our policy that e-mail messages contain an "unsubscribe" function, along with instructions on how to execute the opt-out function. In addition, all website users have the ability to opt-out of receiving e-mail messages by updating their communications preferences within the secured area of the website.

After completing the log-in process, Electronics Portal, i-Design Web, and Customer Center users have the option to change their password, e-mail address, and security question and response. If the website user forgets or misplaces their password, HydraForce will use the security question and response to identify the website user and grant access to the website. To change personally identifiable information collected through various web forms, a person must contact [**HFMarketing@hydraforce.com**](mailto:HFMarketing@hydraforce.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20and%20Terms%20of%20Use).

We recognize that when website users choose to provide personal information, they trust that we will protect their privacy and will provide them with choices about how that information is to be shared. HydraForce will not sell, trade, or rent the personal information that you provide unless you authorize us to do so.

There are instances in which HydraForce may disclose website user's personal information to our distributors, employees, and third-party partners to enable them to perform functions on our behalf. These companies are only permitted to share, store and/or use personal information for business purposes.

We may share your personal information when we believe that such action is necessary to: 1) fulfill an enquiry; 2) protect or defend our legal rights or property, this website, or other users; or 3) protect your health and safety or the health and safety of this website's users or the general public. 

Technology use on this website:

Information about you and your use of this website is collected through the use of session and persistent cookies. Session cookies are small text files that are stored within your computer’s memory. These files are used to facilitate your navigation throughout this website.

Persistent cookies are small computer files that are transferred to your computer's hard drive. These stored files are used in the generation of data that is fed to a contracted third party for website usage analysis. Reports created using this information will provide HydraForce with a better understanding of the use of this website.

HydraForce may work with third party service providers who may place third party persistent cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies on your computer as a visitor to our website to collect information about the use of our website. This information allows these third party service providers to customize our content and advertising. We do not permit these companies to collect any personal information about you using these technologies.

Opting out from these services will have no effect on your use of this website in any way. Information stored within both session and persistent cookies is not tied to your Personally Identifiable Information.

If you are concerned about the storage and use of cookies, you may be able to direct your Internet browser to notify you and seek approval whenever a cookie is being sent to your hard drive. You may also delete a cookie manually from your hard drive through your Internet browser or other programs. You can also set your browser to refuse all cookies.

To gauge the effectiveness of this website, we may collect non-personal information about our website users. This information may include, among other things, your: IP address, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), domain names, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, Device type, Device Operating System (OS) version, Device name, region, and other data. We may use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the website, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically collected data to personal information. 

Internal security procedures:

Information that you review on the i-Design Web, Customer Center, and Electronics Portal site is kept strictly confidential and fully secure. Your encrypted (encoded) information is protected using "Secure Socket Layers (SSL)" as it passes between your browser and this website. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. Only authorized persons are permitted to access your personal information. All authorized persons must abide by security, privacy, and confidentiality agreements. 

E-mail:

If you send questions or comments to an e-mail address listed within this website or via a contact form located within this website, we will share your correspondence with an associate most capable of addressing your questions and concerns. We will retain your communications until we have done our very best to provide you with a complete and satisfactory response. Ultimately, we will either discard your communication or archive it within our marketing automation service. We will not keep your e-mail address for secondary purposes. All information and correspondence you share with us will be handled in the strictest confidence.

We may agree that e-mail has become a standard communication tool used by many different parties. Unfortunately by design standard Internet e-mail is not secure. For that reason, please do not use unsecured e-mail to communicate information to us that you may consider to be confidential.

European Union (EU) General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR):

Residents of the European Union (EU) , under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) have the right to request to modify, delete or access data we collect about them. GDPR took effect on May 25, 2018. To make a request, contact HydraForce Marketing at [**HFMarketing@hydraforce.com**](mailto:HFMarketing@hydraforce.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20and%20Terms%20of%20Use). HydraForce will respond to these requests within 40 days. In case of a data breach, HydraForce will notify customers within 72 hours

California privacy law:

Residents of the State of California, under certain provisions of the California Civil Code, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third-parties to which the company has disclosed certain personally identifiable information as defined under California law during the preceding year for third-party direct marketing purposes. You are limited to one request per calendar year. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. You may request the information in writing by contacting the HydraForce Marketing at [**HFMarketing@hydraforce.com**](mailto:HFMarketing@hydraforce.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20and%20Terms%20of%20Use).

Internet Privacy Statement changes:

This Internet Privacy Statement is effective as of January 2011 and was last updated in May 2018. This Internet Privacy Statement is not intended to and does not create any contractual or other legal rights with or on behalf of any party.

If we decide to change this website's privacy practices, we will post those changes to this Internet Privacy Statement, the home page, and other places that we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information is being collected, how the information is being used, and under what circumstances, if any, the information may be disclosed. HydraForce reserves the right to modify this Internet Privacy Statement at any time, so please review it frequently. 

More information:

This website is maintained by HydraForce, 500 Barclay Blvd, Lincolnshire, IL 60069
